hello my name is grian and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft
I don't know where my stuff's gone I
think I've actually worked through all
of my diamond armor so I look a bit
silly right now might as well take this
stuff off there we go normal skin pretty
dangerous but I'm sure we'll live the
first thing we're going to do in today's
episode is get rid of this but I
actually need to go and grab the rule
book from mumbo's base which I believe
he left in a chest for me I just didn't
pick it up so this is the first thing
we're gonna do now we've only got 27
fireworks which is not a lot
it's not a lot at all so we're gonna
have to be very conservative with them
very conservative which is why I'm just
going to Glide to mumbo's base and not
overdo it okay we can we nail it
I forgot I forgot that I take damage
whoops
got the rule book
and now we need to go and find someone
to tag I wonder if we can launch
ourselves up
ah no
we've got 25 fireworks to find someone
and tag them and this is going to be
Majestic if we don't do it on these
fireworks we're in trouble and the
problem is I don't know where everybody
is I did say last episode that I was
going to tag someone on a completely
different island or a different District
but since I don't have many Rockets I
might just see if Scar's next door if
he's not we're gonna have a look
somewhere else
scar there he is is he AFK
he looks AFK
oh oh come on dude
AFK my dude
I can't tag an AFK it's against the
rules the self-imposed rules we're down
to 19 and we're not finding anybody I
almost think it might be a better idea
to find someone on foot and then go and
launch myself into the air and chase
them down because this is the quickest
way to find someone but I'm using all of
my stuff just to do it
there's someone
I found someone I don't know who it is
I don't know who it is
but there they are next
this is gonna be tough oh wait did I
just see a horse
I'm pretty sure I just saw a horse
[Laughter]
oh Carl
Oh I thought you were my next victim I'm
sorry my dude I didn't mean it
uh we're gonna have to find someone the
old-fashioned way oh
wait uh we're up we're up we're up
foreign
oh what the what
I just I do I oh I was just about to hit
him I don't think he's here anymore that
was the strangest thing he teleported
there to there and then just vanished I
I think we should just still go and find
someone because we still got an
opportunity I was so close to being able
to get him looks like yes I see someone
see I don't know exactly if they're
recording but we're gonna go in for the
swoop
we ready we need to go quite slow need
to do a slow descent
I don't know how to do this
who is it stress monster
come on
no
hide hide hide hide hide that that
nothing I didn't fail I didn't fail at
all
you saw nothing and she's AFK
oh she said of course
this is harder than I thought
this is harder than I thought I just
thought of something though if someone
is going around with the tag all you got
to do is go AFK and then they can't get
you bit of a loophole in the whole thing
right so we've had two failed attempts
one of them wasn't my fault one of them
I just messed up majorly I see him I see
him
can I do it no no he's ready he knows
right we've got three more Rockets we've
got a couple of attempts at this
I I refuse to tag someone normally now
we've got to get him but he's is he
hiding in there
he's hiding in there somewhere I can
sense it I've conceded that Cub has won
this round because I've run out of
fireworks
I am fortunate enough that Tango here is
going to give me a bunch of oh oh God
I'm gonna give him this
oh he's giving me so much gunpowder oh
this is brilliant this is absolutely
brilliant that was a very quick exchange
thank you very much Tango okay so now
all we got to do put the gunpowder and
we got a lot of fireworks
if that's not enough I don't know what
is
there's stress monster
that's stress monster there but again
AFK it's got
and
I got it oh yes I got him I got him
yes
haha
tagged my boy
[Laughter]
success success so we have successfully
tagged iskau now and iskel is pretty
much a rival to me in trouble making
and I'm excited to see what iscal is
going to do once he has come up with a
plan to tag somebody
oh oh
no no no no no no no no no no no no
oh my goodness
oh my goodness the Phantoms
oh that's not good oh that's not good
oh I need to I need to get my diamond
armor back to full oh that was
terrifying can I have a fight mid-air
with these Phantoms
that's gonna be so cool but I need to I
need to get more Health First we could
do this
ah ow okay maybe not Maybe not maybe
this is a date this is amazing thanks
this girl because this is dangerous now
we're in dangerous territory Okay so
that's gonna go on the bucket list
that's going that is 100 going on the
bucket list okay mission accomplished
everybody I've given him the rule book
whoa what's going on there
I've given in the rule book and I have
given him everything he needs so I've
connected up this platform here with a
couple of water elevators which are
easily the best way to get around and
I've made this very short tunnel doesn't
take long to get across at all and it
links pretty much directly up with my
base so it's pretty handy and we're
gonna pop here number six killer Phantom
while flying and elytra that is going to
be an excellent challenge because that
was scary I'm gonna need to get myself
some diamond armor and actually repair
some of this stuff so this is going to
be the layout and it's basically one
giant circle now this doesn't look like
it that one looks like it's shorter but
it's not I promise and I'm gonna
actually hop into another world to show
you the design that I'm gonna go for but
first I actually want to go and fly over
I know I said I wasn't going to use the
elytra too much but I know mumbo's been
working on a base and oh
really
let's try that again I I'll get used to
elytra at some point I promise let's try
again
oh okay so I know that mumbo's been
working on a giant base oh my goodness
there it is and I kind of want to take a
look at it first so that oh my goodness
this is massive
oh wow so I wanted to get a good look at
this before I start mine because we are
working together on some projects it
might be cool eventually to link up our
bases so I don't want to go too far out
of the norm here it looks like it's a
little bit squashed it could do with
maybe being a couple of blocks higher I
think but on the hull
that's not bad
that's really not bad
this is going to be a really cool base I
imagine I don't know what his big plans
are for it but I'm really intrigued so
actually mumbo's and I's base are fairly
fairly similar which is interesting mine
is actually going to be more of a
cylinder whereas he's gone for a sphere
mixed with a bit of hexagon action
and there he is himself I don't know
what he's up to
[Music]
hey Mama let's go and say hello shall we
oh
I forgot about full damage again oh I
had 40 levels oh no
[Laughter]
oh that's so typical what you've got to
remember is that whenever I've used
elytra in Minecraft I've always been in
creative mode so dive bombing has always
just been a thing that I could do
without harm well that was quite a way
to say hello no tigrian dive bombing out
of the sky kills you and I've lost 40
levels 40 levels his base does look cool
look at that that is a very impressive
looking thing so I assume that he's
gonna like build from that Island to
that one and then hopefully he should be
able to see my Island from his furthest
one so yeah this this could work
has he taken my elytra I paid good money
for that
he's taking the mick out of my shovel
having efficiency too and I was like
well yeah but where are your wings
oh my goodness uh that was brilliant so
Mumbo clearly knows how to fly better
than me Builders weren't Made to Fly I
don't think so how do you okay let's go
in a bit gently more gently ow still did
it
so mumbo's saying that he doesn't really
like the octagon shape that's going on
with his base
and he might have a point it is very
very rigid
but it depends what his ultimate goal is
I personally think it could work but it
depends on what his ultimate vision is
for this build you know I'm basically
saying now what's your ultimate plan
here because if it's a death star I
could get on board with that the
he said it may become a Death Star
so he's gonna connect I assume these
islands up because these are all
belonging to Mumbo
and then this is my base out here oh it
does look really small
it does look really small
if we look at the proximity
mumbo's mumbos is bigger numbers is a
lot bigger
my ones really Diddy really Diddy
I did wonder about making it bigger but
I was like hmm if I start something too
big will I finish it this looks
ridiculous look at this
yeah I think I'm gonna have to make this
bigger at least by another 10 blocks
because my plan well actually yeah let's
go and talk about my plan
and slowly descend
nailed it so at the moment this is the
size of the base as it stands it's 33
block radius so from the middle to here
is 33 blocks and that's what it would
look like when I put it together now
this does seem like quite a big space
and it is but the plan here is to bring
it upwards quite High let's say 20
blocks so it won't actually be a
cylinder the whole point of this design
is that it's going to slowly sort of
lean outwards
like almost like a flower
so imagine that it does that all the way
around so the entire shape of this base
will lean out across there
so I've just done a bunch of cylinders
to try and create a shape now this isn't
accurate at all this is not accurate
I've just done some very quick cylinders
remember we're just trying to get a
basic shape so the idea is that this
entire cylinder is going to stretch
outwards and then there's going to be a
bit of like a circle it probably will
end up more this kind of shape
than anything I just did a bunch of
cylinders to try and take it uh in a bit
but that's probably more like the shape
it's going to end up being so then that
goes around and then we're gonna do
another layer
so we've got another cylinder now also
made out of glass I'm not entirely sure
how tall to make each layer maybe this
one needs to be a bit on the smaller
side or maybe they need to all be equal
I'm not sure this one will also Edge out
and lean out into the open area to give
it a bit of shape like so
and we're basically going to repeat this
pattern
maybe twice so one two and then another
one on top
and finally probably three layers is
what I'm thinking to give it its full
height and after reviewing it it's a
really good job that we've done this I
think this layer needs to be the
smallest and it needs to get
incrementally larger so this one is
probably gonna be like 15 blocks high
then 20 maybe even 25 on the final one
it's really hard to tell now this does
not look good I'm not even gonna pretend
like it looks good this is just a good
idea to get a sense of the scale that
I'm going to be building at it doesn't
have any detail it doesn't have anything
further but there's something else that
will be like a really important part of
this let's Top This bit off here before
we add one of the biggest features of
this okay so we kind of get the idea it
looks a little bit like a modern cake
but trust me it's gonna look slightly
different to this one of the biggest
things that I'm going to add is
three really big towers and it's
actually going to be a diagonal now the
perfect diagonal here is right here so
something along the lines of this is
going to be added to the sphere
so the towers need to be taller than the
middle bit but they also need to be not
too short so they really do need to be
quite imposing so I'm thinking maybe a
hundred blocks tall that would work
quite well
this should look really cool I'm just a
little bit scared because even though
this isn't the full thing it's not
looking as good as perhaps I imagined it
but these things often have a way of
working themselves out and if it fails
I can always just blow up and start
again but this is a lot of resources I
haven't collected nearly enough glass to
do what I need to do I really haven't so
this is the basic concept remember
there's gonna be three towers and this
really looks like some sort of Tony
Stark headquarters that we're making
here
all right I think this is a good good
opportunity to really just crack on with
it and see what we can come up with all
right let's head back into hermitcraft
I'm actually really scared to get
started on this I really really am
because well it's not it's not as simple
as just going for it like I did in the
test world because I have commands I can
undo them redo them once I put something
in it's a bit more final
I've always been pretty good at
freestyling but now I think it's time to
just go for it
so let's just let's just go one
well I've slightly messed up because the
platform stops a bit short but while I'm
building this it's a good opportunity to
kind of let you guys know that I'm
actually going to be going away for
about a week and there will still be
videos I've been preparing really really
hard I've been obviously focusing on
hermitcraft a lot because I've been
enjoying it to no end but it does mean
that when you see the videos in the
coming week it will be videos that are
pre-recorded so any interactions or
anything like that they will have
happened a while ago so the reactions
might be a bit delayed or something like
that okay and that's pretty much it for
the circle this is gonna be the base
layer of what we're working on it
doesn't look particularly big does it it
really doesn't look big and that's a
slight concern actually that it's not
big enough I mean that's going to be a
lot of resources on its own
but I'm just sort of thinking about how
it's going to fit in in the grand scheme
of things is it gonna is that too small
maybe that's the second layer that is
this big I mean just comparing it to the
size of mumbo's Base
look at this
absolutely massive absolutely massive
but my one not so much but then I guess
the inside of mine is going to be a huge
functional space I don't know if mumbo's
just going to keep that as a mostly open
sphere of some kind
so mine's more of a solid structure
I'm wondering if it even needs to be
just a couple of blocks bigger just a
couple
hmm
so the idea here is to kind of make a
little base that the whole building is
going to sit on but this is a very
precious material and I'm racking
through this very quickly but I'm pretty
happy with this so to make it solid I'm
just gonna put water all over it and
then it's going to solidify hopefully
yep as it touches it it turns into white
concrete itself
so this is a pretty quick way just by
using the powder as a source building
block rather than like because otherwise
I'd have to take this concrete powder
next to us water source and then mine it
to acquire that and then use this block
to place it in wherever I need it to be
so it's just a bit more of a lengthy
process than building it in the sand
first place and then just placing some
water it'll drip down and then it will
be all sorted I think the other thing
worth mentioning while I'm lugging away
trying to build this as quickly as
possible is I don't want my entire
hermitcraft episodes to just be building
this let me get this straight this is a
huge project and as I'm bulking up
content for my little trip away there's
no way that I'm just gonna make entire
episodes dedicated to building this this
is going to be hundreds and hundreds of
hours of work so I'm gonna have to find
other things to occupy me for these
episodes while while this is sort of
ticking away in the background I do want
to get this really really underway and
that's what we're doing now
but I I am I know what the design is
that I want to make I kind of showed it
to you
but I don't think that I've actually got
it under control at all I think that
I've made this too small and it might
end up being incredibly underwhelming
and that seriously worries me but I have
a contingency plan it'll mean more work
in the future but I have a contingency
plan
if things don't go well
and this looks too small I'm going to
make an entire bigger segment underwater
yep that's what I've decided I'm going
to do so if this turns out to look wrong
we're gonna make another one underwater
which that's a tomorrow Green's problem
that's not a today green problem
it's kind of hard for me to explain what
I'm doing right now because I honestly
I'm just freestyling and I don't really
know where this is going quite yet so it
might be a little bit of a bear with me
here I'm making stuff up
my my idea here is to just bring because
I feel like this circle is that little
bit too small my idea is basically to
have this pillar system go extend
outwards a little bit and then
have that that be the base this would be
the top of the base of it and it would
be slightly bigger than this circle here
I'm just still trying to work out the
Kinks
okay and I think that's where we're
probably going to leave today's episode
this sort of progress is going to take a
really long time to make so for the most
part I'm going to be building this
slowly off camera over time and wait
hold on a second
what's
hold on who's who's touched this who has
touched
oh is this one of them Bumbo things
I don't know Bumbo
I know Mumbo but I don't know a Bumbo I
I think it's a joke from a previous
season I think there was like season
five that they all made these things
that with a mustache and they were
called Bumbo so I guess this would be
Bumbo squid only
I I don't know the meme I'm not sure I
can be part of this because I wasn't
involved in this but you know what this
is such a dashing mustache
is it made out of coal
oh
it's a coal mustache that you don't get
much more manly than that he's been down
there mining in the mines and he's got a
mustache made out of coal I'm gonna
leave that I like it it's gonna end up
being mostly not me at this point that
wasn't me the mustache wasn't me I just
made the Squidward house and it's just
gone on from there I just spotted these
eyebrows I was like what is this anyway
uh this has been a brilliant episode
we've made some progress I can see this
working out really really well I
honestly can
and also it's a good time to mention
that
it's also a really good time to mention
that buildstone the the group that me
and Mumbo are forming together
you guys went nuts with your suggestions
your artwork your fan art
unbelievable but someone actually put
together a really nice idea for a name
and now it but for me this is between
this is the
foreign
and now for me this is a really big deal
now I'm pretty sure that the logo that
we made to begin with now that was just
that was just a tester that was just an
idea it was a prototype it probably
won't end up looking like that
but someone suggested a really cool name
for our group so at the moment
buildstone is the one that I suggested
a user on Twitter a user on Twitter
suggested Architects oh it's brilliant
because it's a Pun It's a pun architect
is obviously someone that makes
buildings but Tech is kind of like the
Redstone sign of things so that is a
proper cool name and also you know
buildstone I I could go either way at
this point so there's going to be a poll
on the video in the top right hand
corner there's a little dot with an I
choose which one you prefer buildstone
which is literally building and Redstone
put together very creative of me of
course or Architects which is like
architect and technology which is a
really really good pun and depending on
which one we choose we'll make a new
logo for it as we see fit and then we're
gonna sort of line them all up or like
come up with a few different designs and
decide which one is going to be the
final one we're in the very very early
infancy of the architect or the
buildstone group The Little collab
between me and Mumbo is in its infancy
we haven't really discussed too much
about what we're going to do yet so this
is a good opportunity to have a say in
how this is going to pan out I need to
light this up ASAP or go to sleep at
least because otherwise I'm gonna get
really annoyed because fixing problems
is a lot harder than just making them in
the first place
ah well that was easy well that is the
end of today's episode I'm going to
continue replicating this all the way
around and take a look at the supplies
because I've taken a big chunk out of
the white concrete powder Supply I
haven't even got started on the glass
yeah I feel like this isn't going to end
well for my supplies at all
this this is this is this is the
foundation not even the
start of anything this is just this the
the very first layer and I'm already
running out of materials so this is
probably a really good idea as I could
just fill this in with a block maybe
packed ice or ice itself or the glass I
do want it to be slightly different to
the rest of it so maybe packed ice or
normal ice and I can use the inside of
this as my base for the time being until
we really get going and we're able to do
a bit more so that's it from me thank
you very much for watching everyone I
hope you enjoyed this video and I'll see
you in hermitcraft episode six goodbye